Jared Augastine Makario | Curriculum Vitae Webpage: jaredmakario.com Telephone: +254727048251 Email: jaredmaks@gmail.com

Professional profile.

I am an Electrical and Electronic graduate engineer. Being in the field of Engineering and technology, I have embraced innovations in fields like telecommunication, IoT, artificial intelligence, machine learning, deep learning, data science, software development and renewable energy to bridge engineering and digital transformation gap. I have also worked in fields pertaining to power generation, transmission, protection, controls, marketing, billing and maintenance, designs of efficient and sustainable grids, conservation of energy, water and environment protection. In my career development I trained in a busy power production company, research and information technology firm as well as a Radio station.

Work Experience.

Center for Data Science and Artificial Intelligence (DSAIL) - Dedan Kimathi University of Technology Nyeri, Kenya

Software Engineer Intern - (Developer)

January 2020 -

June 2020

- Building Artificial Intelligence web application solutions
- Image processing with deep learning algorithms
- Data analysis and visualization
- Building data pipelines
- Cloud servers handling and Iot Platforms

Networks for Learning Africa Ltd

Nyeri, Kenya

Software and Hardware Engineer- (Developer)

Feb 2019 – August 2019

- Creating websites and web applications to consume Internet of Things (IoT) data.
- Designing IoT hardware devices and fabrication for remote deployment and data collection.
- Programming IoT devices for agriculture, energy, asset tracking, facility management and water conservation applications.
- Running and operating cloud servers and databases.
- Research on Long range Wide Area Network (LoRAWAN)

Homeboyz Entertainment Ltd

Nairobi, Kenya

Data Scientist -Intern.

Feb 2018 – May 2018

- Building data science infrastructure to store, curate, clean, analyse and visualize data for administrative decision making purposes.
- Development of reactive web applications for clients and internal use.
- Performing twitter sentimental analysis and mapping for Radio shows.
- Fixing IT problems in the company.
- Designing and building machine learning systems.
- Social media data mining

Iberafrica (EA) Power Ltd

Nairobi, Kenya

Control and operations Engineer- Intern

Jan 2017 – April 2017

- Conducting preventive electrical maintenance, isolation and protection.
- Testing of cables at substations.
- Operating PLCs, SCADA systems and information interpretation.
- Servicing of motors, purifiers, cooling system, boilers and lube oil separators.
- Starting and stopping of Engines for power dispatch.
- Reverse Osmosis (RO) operation and General plant monitoring.

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

Nyeri, Kenya

Sept 2014 – April 2019

Student leader- (Class Representative).

- Administration on student welfare.
- Conveying and bridging information channels between students and administration.
- Organising and managing student activities.

Education

B.Sc. Electrical and Electronic EngineeringUndergraduate Degree. Dedan Kimathi University of Technology Sept 2014 – April 2019

- Taking courses relating to electrical and electronic engineering.
- Co-authored a conference paper titled 'Long Range Low Power Sensor Networks for Agricultural Monitoring A Case Study in Kenya'.

Human Research Data or Specimens Only Research (Course)

CITI-MIT

Research course

Jan 2020

• Taking course on human subjects research ethics and policies

Computer Skills and Languages

- Programming; C/C++, Python, html, Css, PhP, java, bootstrap and Scala.
- Matlab, Git, pycharm, code blocks, sublime text.
- Pspice, Power World, Constructor, Proteus, Eagle, Circuitmaker, Kicard, Drawing and design.
- Researching.
- Web applications, website design and development, AWS, GCP, Azure, IBM and kaa cloud servers management.

Working Knowledge:

- Hadoop, Mesos, Akka, Kafka, Apache Spark and other open source data handling tools.
- Jupyter notebooks, google colaboratory, github, bitbucket, SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Tableau, Grafana, Chronograf and Keyhole.
- Electrical systems design, control and maintenance.

Languages: English and Kiswahili.

Achievements and Activities.

Hackers.io May 2020

Covid-19 detect and protect challenge 2020

• Wrote a winning fever surveillance proposal.

Capital Market University Challenge 2018

2018/2019

CMA University Challenge 2018/2019

• CMA 2018 university challenges university representative DeKUT, Kenya.

World Energy Day (WED).

Oct 2018

WED University Student Energy Innovation Challenge, Kenya

• Won the world energy day student energy innovation challenge 2018 (2nd runners up).

Data Science Africa.

Summer school workshop, Kenya

May 2018- June 2018

- Trained on data science, machine learning and IoT.
- Gave a presentation on IoT and data science projects.
- Building Internet of Things (IoT) prototypes and doing remote deployment for data collection at the university.

Data Science Africa.

Summer school. Tanzania

July 2017

• Trained on Artificial intelligence, machine learning, IoT and data science methods.

Hobbies and Interests.

- Programming
- Researching
- Blogging on technology https://medium.com/@jaredmaks

References.

Available on request